Taylor Welling

Front-end Web Developer & Designer Bellevue, WA

tayrwelling@gmail.com +1 (605) 270-1773 taylorwelling.com github.com/tw3080 linkedin.com/in/taylorwelling

Summary:

Creative problem-solver with a passion for combining design and technical skills to build exceptional user experiences. Strives to produce content which is aesthetically pleasing and functional, and takes pride in using empathy to understand projects from the user's perspective. Possesses a strong drive for self-improvement and an openness to ideas and input from others; an excellent member of any team.

Development Proficiencies:

HTML5 | CSS3 | LESS | JavaScript | AngularJS | jQuery | Node.js | Express | MongoDB

Design Proficiencies:

Responsive Web Design | UI / UX Design | Wireframing

Software Experience:

Adobe Photoshop | Adobe Illustrator | Git/GitHub

Projects:

Poké Mongo (October 2016)

- Allows Pokémon card collectors to quickly view and manage their cards online
- Users can sign up, login, and search for cards to add to their virtual collection
- Developed with HTML5, CSS3/LESS, JavaScript (ES6), AngularJS, Node.js, Express, and MongoDB

Weather Mood (August 2016)

- Weather app with changing styles and white noise sounds based on weather conditions
- Designed to be unobtrusive and relaxing; concisely displays only the most essential weather information
- Users can search for locations and save their favorite cities for quick viewing
- Developed with HTML5, CSS3/LESS, JavaScript, and AngularJS

Mappr (July 2016)

- An interactive gallery and map of Flickr photos which integrates the Flickr API and Google Maps API to display photos based on locations searched for by the user
- Developed with HTML5, CSS3/LESS, JavaScript, and jQuery

Education:

Thinkful (May 2016 - December 2016)

Remote

- Full-stack Web Development
- Project-based curriculum with guidance from 1-on-1 mentorship

Bellevue College (April 2015 - May 2016)

Bellevue, WA

- Completed 45 credits
- Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

San Jacinto College (August 2011 - May 2013)

Pasadena, TX

- Completed 48 credits
- Dean's List fall '11, spring '12, fall '12

Experience:

Crew Member

Trader Joe's | Bellevue, WA (October 2016 - Present)

- Create a fun, welcoming customer experience by sharing product knowledge, walking customers to items, and answering questions/offering suggestions
- Demonstrate flexibility by performing multiple roles including working a cash register, stocking shelves, or building displays

Food Server

Scotty Browns Restaurant | Bellevue, WA (August 2014 - October 2015) Olive Garden | Everett, WA (November 2013 - August 2014)

- Partnered with team members to deliver exceptional, friendly service to guests in a fast-paced and time-sensitive environment
- Maintained a positive, professional attitude and efficiently multi-tasked in hectic situations